Guide to the Deborah Rawson papers, 1947-2007
Rawson, Deborah papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Deborah Rawson papers, 1947-2007.
8462
Rawson, Deborah
4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, diaries, newspapers, photographs, printed materials, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes student notebooks and papers from grade school through college, photographs, letters to Rawson, subject files, and articles written by her.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1968. After graduating from Cornell, Deborah Rawson traveled to Japan, where she studied flower arranging and the tea ceremony. She returned to the U.S. to work on a master's degree from Hunter College and worked as a journalist for publications including Harper's Bazaar, "New York Talk," "On the Next Wave," and the Japanese edition of Cosmopolitan. In 1989, she published a book about her Vermont heritage, Without a Farmhouse Near. Deborah Rawson died in 1992. A room in the Carl A. Kroch Library is named in her memory.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes student notebooks and papers from grade school through college, photographs, letters to Rawson, subject files, and articles written by her.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rawson, Deborah, 1947-2004.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University. Class of 1968.
Subjects:
Women college students -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.
Places:
Japan -- Description and travel.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Personal correspondence, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Personal correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Personal correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Personal correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Personal correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Personal correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Personal correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Personal correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Personal correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Personal correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Personal correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Personal correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Personal correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Personal correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Personal correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Personal correspondence, 1981-2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Personal correspondence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Personal correspondence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Personal correspondence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Personal correspondence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Congratulation cards - Deborah's birth, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Birthday cards - Deborah's first birthday, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letters to Deborah, from friends, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Condolence cards, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cards from Chuck, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Special occasion cards to Jessie and Burnett, from Deborah, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Cards to Deborah, from Jessie and Burnett, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Blank cards, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Grade school work, ca. 1960's (Box 2, Folder 9)
- High school/college work, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- High school/college work, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Thesis, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Pearl River High School items, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- High school diploma, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Additional grade school material, ca. 1960's; Small box (Box 2)
- Proposals, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Interviews, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, drafts, proofs, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, drafts, proofs, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, drafts, proofs, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, drafts, proofs, 1990's, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, drafts, proofs, 1990's, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Additional correspondence, 1980-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Additional drafts, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Articles by Deborah Rawson, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Articles by others, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Articles by others, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Joseph Brodsky items, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Biographies, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Rawson fund and family reunion, 1991, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Deborah Rawson Memorial Library, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Cornell Cinema, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Guggenheim summer internship, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Report on Physicians for Human Rights mission to Israel, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Rawson room dedication, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Athletic achievement certificate, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Japanese study aids (Japanese 4006), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Unidentified items, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous items, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Poems, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Journals, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Journals, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Journals, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Photos, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Student notebooks, ca. 1960's-1970's (Box 4)
- Cornell diploma, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Photo of Deborah Rawson room wall hanging, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Ikenobo floral art certificates, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Deborah Rawson plaque (Box 5)
- Additional estate materials (Box 5)
  Clippings, pictures of house, correspondence with Cornell regarding scholarship. Also an article by Rawson in Manhattan East newspaper.